<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[WebComponents.org]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[A place to discuss and evolve Web Component best-practices]]></description>
        <link>http://localhost:9778</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 01:59:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:9778/podcasts.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 01:58:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[21: The X-Tag Project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Daniel Buchner, Product Manager at Target &amp; former Mozillian, talks with
The Web Platform Podcast on x-tag, the Custom Elements library competitor
to Polymer that he created alongside former Mozillian &amp; Kraken Developer,
Arron Schaar. X-tag is a interesting way to work with web components that
takes a totally imperative approach to creating Web Components as opposed
to the declarative way of building with Polymer. Some features include
legacy browser support, optional mixins to share across components, &amp;
functional pseudos to assist in delegation.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-21_the-xtag-project.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/21-the-x-tag-project</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/21-the-x-tag-project</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20: Mozilla Brick, ‘UIKit’ for The Web]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Matt Claypotch, Mozilla Apps Engineer &amp; Lead on Mozilla Brick Project and Soledad Penades,
GIF Hacktivist &amp; Mozilla Apps Engineer, join The Web Platform Podcast to talk about building
UI focused Web Components for the &#39;Mobile First&#39; Web Development. Mozilla Brick is a set of
&#39;Mobile First&#39; focused Web Components built as close to the specs as possible. It is not a
library built on top of Web Components like Polymer, it is a collection of elements with as
little abstraction as possible. Brick&#39;s goal has been to make building the interface of web
applications easier. UI is not as easy for many developers to build from scratch and it can be
difficult to get performant, usable, and attractive widgets.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-20-mozilla-brick-uikit-for-the-web.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/20-mozilla-brick-uikit-for-the-web</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/20-mozilla-brick-uikit-for-the-web</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[141: With Marcy Sutton]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Shop Talk Show is joined by Marcy Sutton. Marcy is a interactive
developer at Substantial in Seattle. We take a deep dive into
web components, accessibility, Angular JS, AJAX, ARIA, and more!</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://audio.simplecast.fm/6424.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/141-with-marcy-sutton</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/141-with-marcy-sutton</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[14: Web Components Interop and Polymer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Today, Web Components have emerged from cutting edge technologies to technologies
we can implement in our small scale production. It won’t be long before we are
building large scale applications with Custom Elements, HTML Imports, Template Tags,
and the infamous Shadow DOM. In embracing this type of developer environment, with
it’s flexibility and compositional nature, consider interoperabilty as a core concept.</p>
<p>Rob Dodson, Google Engineer, goes through many of the changes made to Polymer 0.4.2,
including accessibility and performance enhancements that help in making applications more
integrated and how Google is working to share what the Blink Team has learned from implementing
Web Components in Chrome with other browser vendors and developers.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-14_web-components-interop-and-polymer.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/14-web-components-interop-and-polymer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/14-web-components-interop-and-polymer</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[86: Customizing the Web with Rob Dodson]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Web Components are all the rage these days — a way to create the web
using chunks of code that are reusable across projects. Polymer is a
polyfill for using Web Components today. Rob Dodson joins Jen Simmons
to explain the current landscape.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://fdlyr.co/d/webahead/cdn.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/webahead/2014/webahead-086.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/customizing-the-web-with-rob-dodson</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/customizing-the-web-with-rob-dodson</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11: The Bosonic Project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Raphael Rougeron joins The Web Platform Podscast from Toulouse, France to talk about The Bosonic Project.
Raphael and his team of developers mostly focus their development efforts working in the Financial Industry,
building out secure and robust applications as well as intricate cross browser UI Components. The UI
components part of his work is especially interesting in that it led him to create The Bosonic Project, an alternative
type of Web Components library that takes a different approach than Polymer or x-Tag.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-11_the-bosonic-project.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/11-the-bosonic-project</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/11-the-bosonic-project</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9: Web Accessibility for JavaScript Components and Custom Elements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Steve Faulkner of The Paciello Group and Marcy Sutton from Substantial discuss the lack of focus in product development
today with regards to building accessible applications &amp; services. Many times web accessibility becomes an afterthought in
creating a software product, having little prioritization from the business side until it is a problem. Retrofitting such
an important part of our development can make web accessibility seem more like a chore with low ROI for the the time taken
to implement it. It can be easy if developers know how to do it and hardly any work when it is successfully incorporated
into a development process and it’s valued at the business level.</p>
<p>In many client side frameworks there is a growing focus on componentization in the form of  HTML elements. Some examples
are Angular Directives, Ember Components, and React Classes. Web Components, a low level set of native web technologies,
give developers a chance to build better Web Accessibile components. Using various tools like WAI ARIA roles at a more focused
&amp; reusable level, Web Components may just be the future of accessibility on the web.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-9_web-accessibility-for-javascript-components-and-custom-elements.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/9-web-accessibility-for-javascript-components-and-custom-elements</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/9-web-accessibility-for-javascript-components-and-custom-elements</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[124: With Rob Dodson]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Shop Talk Show is joined by Rob Dodson. Rob works on Polymer
at Google. True Facts. We take a deep dive with him into Polymer
and Web Components.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://audio.simplecast.fm/6407.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/124-with-rob-dodson</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/124-with-rob-dodson</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[120: Google Polymer with Rob Dodson and Eric Bidelman]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The JavaScript Jabber Panel discusses the Polymer Project
with guests Rob Dodson &amp; Eric Bidelman who work on the
project at Google. They discussion the components, frameworks,
&amp; libraries available to developers as well the strengths and
weaknesses of web components</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://media.devchat.tv/js-jabber/JSJ120GooglePolymer.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/google-polymer-with-rob-dodson-and-eric-bidelman</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/google-polymer-with-rob-dodson-and-eric-bidelman</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5: The Web Components Community]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Web Components are a set of emerging and rapidly changing technologies alter the way many developers are starting to
build web applications. Zeno Rocha, a dominant force in the front end development community talks with
The Web Platform Podcast on how developers can get started building with these technologies today &amp; how to build their
own components. Zeno covers tooling, using Github &amp; Bower, building for the communities, and other front end developer
goodness.</p>
<!-- Excerpt -->

<div class="podcast-wrap">
    <audio controls itemprop="audio">
      <source src="http://traffic.libsyn.com/thewebplatform/episode-5_the-web-components-community.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
</div>]]></description>
            <link>http://localhost:9778/podcasts/5-the-web-components-community</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:9778/podcasts/5-the-web-components-community</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>